<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>openSUSE News</title>
	<atom:link href="https://news.opensuse.org/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://news.opensuse.org</link>
	<description>The latest news from the openSUSE project</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 04:39:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.2.4</generator>
	<item>
		<title>openSUSE.Asia Summit expands with Study Area</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/08/opensuse-asia-summit-expands-with-study-area/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/08/opensuse-asia-summit-expands-with-study-area/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2015 04:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manu Gupta]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19471</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[&#160; The openSUSE.Asia Summit aims to promote Linux in Asia region. This year we are hosting the summit in Taipei City, Taiwan. Study Area, a non-commercial community, aims to educate about Linux, its eco system and other areas of computing, has joined us in our mission to co-host the event. This collaboration will expand the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The openSUSE.Asia Summit aims to promote Linux in Asia region. This year<br />
we are hosting the summit in Taipei <img class="alignright  wp-image-18416" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/terry-crews-yelling-I-want-MOAR-300x300.jpg" alt="Terry Crews Yelling" width="238" height="238" />City, Taiwan. Study Area, a non-commercial community, aims to educate about Linux, its eco system and other areas of computing, has joined us in our mission to co-host the event. This collaboration will expand the frontiers of both the communities into one single mission of promoting both openSUSE and FOSS.</p>
<p><strong>About Study Area</strong></p>
<p>Study Area (SA) was co-founded by lman, V.Bird and Netman in 1999.  SA is aimed at an online IT Learning Center so that novices have a place to find the answers and experts have a place to share knowledge, ranged from networking, programming, web development, database knowledge, Linux, etc.</p>
<p>Study Area has spends a lot of time to promote free and open source software in the country by holding events every month in Taipei and Tainan. Enthusiasts gather members from every corner to meet, learn and share experience and knowledge.</p>
<p>SA related online information</p>
<p>(1) Study-Area <a href="http://study-area.org/menu2.htm">http://study-area.org/menu2.htm</a></p>
<p>(2) SA Forum <a href="http://phorum.study-area.org/">http://phorum.study-area.org/</a></p>
<p>(3) SA IRC Channel + <a href="http://irc.freenode.net/">irc.freenode.net</a> /#study-area</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/08/opensuse-asia-summit-expands-with-study-area/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>openSUSE releases Leap Milestone 2</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/04/opensuse-releases-leap-milestone-2/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/04/opensuse-releases-leap-milestone-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 04 Sep 2015 09:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Douglas DeMaio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19466</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The second milestone for openSUSE’s newest distribution Leap was released today and it’s filled with packages that will interest open-source users everywhere and Linux professionals looking for a long-term, stable Linux system. “Milestone 2 is realistic to use for non-critical production servers,” said members of the openSUSE release team. Doing so, as well has having [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Leap1.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19318" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Leap1-300x300.png" alt="Leap1" width="300" height="300" /></a>The <a href="https://software.opensuse.org/developer" target="_blank">second milestone</a> for openSUSE’s newest distribution <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Leap" target="_blank">Leap</a> was released today and it’s filled with packages that will interest open-source users everywhere and <a href="https://www.linux.com/" target="_blank">Linux</a> professionals looking for a long-term, stable Linux system.</p>
<h4>“Milestone 2 is realistic to use for non-critical production servers,” said members of the openSUSE release team.</h4>
<p>Doing so, as well has having developers, system administrators and users use Milestone 2 will offer a chance to find missing packages and determine where the gaps are in the milestone.</p>
<p>Milestone 2 replaced the complete base system and replaced the full <a href="http://yast.github.io/" target="_blank">YaST</a> stack.</p>
<p><span id="more-19466"></span>New versions in the milestone release include Firefox 40, ThunderBird 38.2, digiKam photo management program 4.11 and the YaST stack of <a href="https://www.suse.com/products/server/features/" target="_blank">SUSE Linux Enterprise 12</a> Service Pack 1.</p>
<p>The latest stable Linux Kernel 4.1.6 is in Milestone 2 and git is updated to version 2.5.0. The kernel-firmware update is 20150715. Apache updates to 2.4.16 and btrfs to 4.1.2.</p>
<p>KDE Plasma has update 15.04.3, which include Long Term Support versions of Plasma Workspaces 4.11.21. GNOME 3.16 has a refresh and Libreoffice 4.3 based on SLE 12 is pending an upgrade to Libreoffice 5. Most versions in Milestone 2 are expected to be the versions in Leap 42.1 when it’s released Nov. 4 at at<a href="http://www.susecon.com/" target="_blank"> SUSECon</a> in Amsterdam, which will no doubt be celebrated with <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Beer" target="_blank">openSUSE Beer</a> during the <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Launch_parties" target="_blank">release party</a>.</p>
<p>Open source enthusiast can expect a toolchain refresh with GNU Compiler Collection 4.8.5 (GCC 5 is optional) and a collection of binary tools from binutils 2.25 and debugger GDB 7.9.1. Makers can build and test software packages with the CMake 3.3.1, which is included in the latest milestone.</p>
<p>Enterprise class database PostgreSQL 9.3.8 and database management system MariaDB 10.0.20 are both in the milestone. Samba 4.1.12 and LVM2 1.02.97 round off the highlighted packages for Milestone 2.</p>
<p>Aligned with SLE 12 SP 1, Leap  version 42.1 will provide the best of both worlds in terms of enterprise packages and stability topped with community innovations from openSUSE’s tested and integrated development architecture.</p>
<p>Leap shares source code from SP1  and a common core SLE. Future minor releases of Leap will align with future SUSE service packs while future major versions of Leap will align with future major versions of SLE.</p>
<p>There are currently more than 6900 packages in Milestone 2 with 600 pending updates.</p>
<p>Developers wanting to include their packages in Leap should ensure their Factory packages are releasable by Sept. 20.</p>
<p>Oct. 1 is the cut off date for allowing packages to change because of licenses and legal reviews.</p>
<p>The RC1 release will be Oct. 15 and the Goldmaster is scheduled for Oct. 30, so translations, release notes and localization of the release should be completed by Oct. 30.</p>
<p>Journalists should contact <a href="mailto:ddemaio@suse.com">ddemaio@suse.com</a> to test the Goldmaster prior to the release.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/04/opensuse-releases-leap-milestone-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>17</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tumbleweed gets three snapshots this week</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/03/tumbleweed-gets-three-snapshots-this-week/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/03/tumbleweed-gets-three-snapshots-this-week/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 10:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Douglas DeMaio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Leap]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[opensuse]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Plasma 5.4]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tumbleweed]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19464</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[During the past week, Tumbleweed had three snapshots and two packages updated to major versions. Perl’s update to version 5.22 in the 20150828 snapshot was perhaps the biggest news for TW this week, which was evident in the tread that followed the snapshot release. The libinput library that handles input devices in Wayland compositors and [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Tumbleweed.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19336" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Tumbleweed-300x300.png" alt="Tumbleweed" width="300" height="300" /></a>During the past week, Tumbleweed had three snapshots and two packages updated to major versions.</p>
<p>Perl’s update to version 5.22 in the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00746.html" target="_blank">20150828 snapshot</a> was perhaps the biggest news for TW this week, which was evident in the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/threads4.html" target="_blank">tread</a> that followed the snapshot release.</p>
<p>The libinput library that handles input devices in <a href="http://wayland.freedesktop.org/">Wayland</a> compositors and generic <a href="http://x.org/">X.Org</a> input drivers upgraded to its first major version in the 20150828 snapshot, which moved from version 0.21 to 1.0. Python-cryptography was another version that updated to version 1.0, which was previously 0.9.3.</p>
<p>In the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00766.html" target="_blank">20150829 snapshot</a>, LibreOffice updated to version 5.0.1.2 and worth mentioning is ExifTool, which is for reading, writing, and manipulating image, audio, and video <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Metadata">metadata</a>, updated to version 10.</p>
<p>In the latest snapshot <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-09/msg00043.html" target="_blank">20150831</a>, the application security tool AppArmor updated to version 20150828.</p>
<p>Users anticipating the release of <a href="https://www.kde.org/announcements/plasma-5.3.95.php" target="_blank">Plasma 5.4</a> will have to wait a little longer; KDE’s newest version is in openSUSE Factory and progress is being made, but there are some tweaks that need to be made before it is released in a TW snapshot.</p>
<h4>The 5.4 version is also expected to be released in openSUSE Leap, which will have its Milestone 2 release tomorrow.</h4>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/09/03/tumbleweed-gets-three-snapshots-this-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Integration process for openSUSE Tumbleweed, Leap explained</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/integration-process-for-opensuse-tumbleweed-leap-explained-2/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/integration-process-for-opensuse-tumbleweed-leap-explained-2/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 09:07:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Douglas DeMaio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19460</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The SUSE office in Nuremberg, Germany, had a special presentation given by Dominique Leuenberger, last week about the interconnecting points of the openSUSE project. Specifically, Leuenberger covered the integration process of Tumbleweed and Leap and explained the difference between the two. “Leap is trying to find the balance between how much SLE (SUSE Linux Enterprise) and how [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/VXwi9IFLvn4" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><br />
<span style="font-weight: 400;">The SUSE office in Nuremberg, Germany, had a special presentation given by </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Dominique Leuenberger, </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">last week about the interconnecting points of the openSUSE project.</span></p>
<p>Specifically, Leuenberger covered the integration process of Tumbleweed and Leap and explained the difference between the two.</p>
<p>“Leap is trying to find the balance between how much SLE (SUSE Linux Enterprise) and how much Tumbleweed,” he said.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Tumbleweed is a tested and stable rolling release with the most recent kernels, software versions and packages while SLE focuses on </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">delivering enterprise-quality technology, efficiency and systems management.</span><span id="more-19460"></span></p>
<p>Leuenberger, who has been in the openSUSE project since it started, further explained how items enter the Open Build Service, are tested and reviewed in the Factory process and then how items receive automated testing in openQA.</p>
<p>“Once openQA is ready, we give this all to our happy users, hopefully, most of the time,” he said. “As usual they always report more bugs, which is why the openSUSE Factory mailing list is really helpful.”</p>
<p>Users of Tumbleweed are recommended to sign up to the openSUSE Factory mailing list to share user experience and get involved with improving and advancing systems to create long-term stability for Free and Open Source Software systems.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The audio and video quality isn’t the high quality, but it is understandable and the slides are readable. The presentation last about 25 minutes and there was about 30 minutes dedicated to the questions about the software development process.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/integration-process-for-opensuse-tumbleweed-leap-explained-2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>openSUSE Asia Summit 2015 Call for Sponsorship</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-call-for-sponsorship/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-call-for-sponsorship/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 05:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manu Gupta]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19451</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The openSUSE.Asia Committee seeks sponsors for the second edition of openSUSE.Asia Summit that will take place in Taipei city, Taiwan from 5th and 6th of December 2015. We expect about 200 attendees ranging from developers, regular users and power users to attend the summit. The sponsorship amount will cover travel costs for speakers and some [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The openSUSE.Asia Committee seeks sponsors for the second edition of openSUSE.Asia Summit that will take place in Taipei city, Taiwan from 5th and 6th of December 2015. We expect about 200 attendees ranging from developers, regular users and power users to attend the summit. The sponsorship amount will cover travel costs for speakers and some attendees, as well as the cost of facilities.</p>
<p><span id="more-19451"></span></p>
<p>The summit aims to provide a free platform for users, contributors and developers from both inside and outside of the openSUSE community fostering ties the open source enthusiasts across communities. Attendees take this opportunity to learn about different modern technologies and share their experiences.</p>
<p>By sponsoring, individuals, businesses, and organizations can show their appreciation the efforts of the openSUSE community and summit volunteers. The sponsorship, is also a great way to</p>
<ul>
<li>Promote your products in the community.</li>
<li>Talk about the product in the business track. It will be a great opportunity for the sponsor to describe their products to FOSS, and the openSUSE community. Businesses can talk about their solutions, and on other topics such as training, exchange of technology and other topics in line with the guiding principles of the summit and openSUSE Project.</li>
<li>Sponsors will be promoted through the following venues
<ul>
<li>Promotion through the openSUSE.Asia Summit website.</li>
<li>Promotion through printed materials advertising the event.</li>
<li>Inclusion of sponsor material in the summit welcome package.</li>
<li>Sponsor promotional advertising visible throughout the event location.</li>
<li>Visibility at other community events that are used to promote openSUSE.Asia summit.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> Sponsors can also request a booth to highlight their products and businesses.</li>
</ul>
<p>For more details on sponsorship, contact Joey Lee (jlee@suse.com) and Max Lin (mlin@suse.com) no later than 19th of October, 2015.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/28/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-call-for-sponsorship/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>openSUSE.Asia Summit – Call for Papers</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/25/opensuse-asia-summit-call-for-papers/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/25/opensuse-asia-summit-call-for-papers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2015 12:31:02 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manu Gupta]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[cfp]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19441</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The openSUSE.Asia Committee is happy to announce the call for papers upcoming second openSUSE.Asia Summit. Starting today, the Committee is looking forward to see your proposals. The committee is looking for speakers from different avenues representing and advocating Free and Open Source Software. Presentations can be submitted in any of the four formats Lightning Talk [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The openSUSE.Asia Committee is happy to announce the call for papers upcoming second openSUSE.Asia Summit. Starting today, the Committee is looking forward to see your proposals. The committee is looking for speakers from different avenues representing and advocating Free and Open Source Software.</p>
<p><strong>Presentations can be submitted in any of the four formats<br />
<img class="alignright size-full wp-image-19136" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/03/secondcall.jpg" alt="secondcall" width="140" height="125" /></strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Lightning Talk (10 mins)</li>
<li>Short Talk (30 mins)</li>
<li>Long Talk (60 mins)</li>
<li>Workshop (3 hours)</li>
</ul>
<p>The openSUSE.Asia committee highly recommends workshops or hands on sessions. Papers can be submitted at the <a href="https://events.opensuse.org/conference/summitasia15" target="_blank">conference website</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Deadlines</strong></p>
<p>Papers can be submitted until 25<sup>th</sup> of September. The openSUSE.Asia Committee will evaluate the proposals based on the submitted abstracts and available time in the schedule, and, the accepted proposals will be announced on 9<sup>th </sup>October.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/25/opensuse-asia-summit-call-for-papers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>openSUSE.Asia Summit 2015 – Logo design contest is back</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/24/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-logo-design-contest-is-back/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/24/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-logo-design-contest-is-back/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2015 22:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manu Gupta]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19426</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Preparations for the openSUSE.Asia Summit are rolling. As we are busy prepping ourselves for this big event, we realized that we need a logo for our very own Summit. Following tradition, we are back with the logo contest. We are looking for a logo which best reflects openSUSE and its community in Asia. The contest [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="western">Preparations for the openSUSE.Asia Summit are rolling. As we are busy prepping ourselves for this big event, we realized that we need a logo for our very own Summit. Following tradition, we are back with the logo contest. We are looking for a logo which best reflects openSUSE and its community in Asia. The contest is open now and ends on <i><b>19 September </b></i><i><b>2015</b></i>. We will send a “Geeko Mystery Box” as an appreciation for the best logo designed.</p>
<p class="western">The <b>Rules</b> of the Contest are as follows:</p>
<p class="western"><img class=" alignright" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/5f/Symbol_thumbs_up_green.png" alt="" width="255" height="286" /></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p class="western">We will accept only SVG format for original design.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">Both color and monochrome(black and white) version are required as part of your submission.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">The elements of your design should reflect the openSUSE community in Asia.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">The logo should avoid the following things:</p>
<ul>
<ul>
<li>
<p class="western">No brand names or trademarks of any kind.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No illustrations that may consider inappropriate, offensive, hateful, tortuous, defamatory, slanderous or libelous.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No sexually explicit or provocative images.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No images of weapons or violence.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No alcohol, tobacco, or drug use imagery.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No designs which promotes bigotry, racism, hatred or harm against groups or individuals; or promotes discrimination based on race, gender, religion, nationality, disability, sexual orientation or age.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">No religious, political, or nationalist imagery.</p>
</li>
</ul>
</ul>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">The logo should comply with “openSUSE Project Trademark Guidelines” published at: <span style="color: #000080;"><span lang="zxx"><u><a href="https://en.opensuse.org/File:OpenSUSE_Trademark_Guidelines.pdf" target="_blank">https://en.opensuse.org/File:OpenSUSE_Trademark_Guidelines.pdf</a></u></span></span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">You should also agree that the openSUSE community have right to interpret the usage of the artwork.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">All your artwork will be licensed under <span style="color: #000080;"><span lang="zxx"><u><a href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/" target="_blank">CC-BY-SA 3.0</a></u></span></span>.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p><span id="more-19426"></span></p>
<p class="western">The following links can be useful to you:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p class="western"><span style="color: #000080;"><span lang="zxx"><u><a href="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Artwork_guidelines" target="_blank">http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Artwork_guidelines</a></u></span></span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western"><span style="color: #000080;"><span lang="zxx"><u><a href="http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Artwork_brand" target="_blank">http://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Artwork_brand</a></u></span></span></p>
</li>
</ul>
<p class="western">Please send your design to <span style="color: #000080;"><span lang="zxx"><u><a href="mailto:opensuse.asia@gmail.com" target="_blank">opensuse.asia@gmail.com</a></u></span></span> with the following entries:</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p class="western">Vector file of the design in attachment, with svg format ONLY.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">Bitmap of design in attachment – image size: <i><b>256*256px</b></i> at least. Format: <i><b>png</b></i> or <i><b>jpg</b></i>. Less than <i><b>512KB</b></i>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">Your name.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">Where are you working/studying now. (optional)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="western">Your phone number. (optional)</p>
</li>
</ol>
<p class="western">After that, the openSUSE.Asia Summit Committee will decide on the logos, subject to the condition, that the logo meets all the requirements. The final decision will be made by openSUSE.Asia Summit Committee and it may not be the highest scored design. We recommend the artist to use Inkscape, a powerful, free and open source vector graphics tool for all kinds of design.</p>
<p>Note: The article has been updated after discussion with openSUSE.Asia team regarding entry rules.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/24/opensuse-asia-summit-2015-logo-design-contest-is-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The weekly review: Tumbleweed gets 4.1.5, TW-shirt at FrOSCon</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/22/the-weekly-review-tumbleweed-gets-4-1-5-tw-shirt-at-froscon/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/22/the-weekly-review-tumbleweed-gets-4-1-5-tw-shirt-at-froscon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 08:52:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Douglas DeMaio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19422</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This week Tumbleweed posted two snapshots in spite of the fact many developers with families had been on holidays before school begins. In those two snapshots, there were changes to  PyQt4 and an upgrade to a newer Kernel. Tumbleweed No major versions were upgraded in the 20150819 Tumbleweed snapshot, but TW did update to Linux [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Tumbleweed.png"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19336" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/07/Tumbleweed-300x300.png" alt="Tumbleweed" width="300" height="300" /></a>This week Tumbleweed posted two snapshots in spite of the fact many developers with families had been on holidays before school begins.</p>
<p>In those two snapshots, there were changes to  PyQt4 and an upgrade to a newer Kernel.</p>
<h4>Tumbleweed</h4>
<p>No major versions were upgraded in the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00450.html" target="_blank">20150819 Tumbleweed snapshot</a>, but TW did update to Linux Kernel 4.1.5.</p>
<p>The <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00398.html" target="_blank">20150815 snapshot</a> there were bug-fixes in PyQt4 for 4.11.4., 4.11.3 and 4.11.2. Added support was also applied for Qt v4.8.6 and there were several other updates.</p>
<h4>FrOSCon</h4>
<p>This weekend, we are at the <a href="http://www.froscon.de/en/home/" target="_blank">Free and Open Source Software Conference</a> at the University of Applied Sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg. Jon “Maddog” Hall, chairman of the non profit Linux International and co-founder of the open source initiative, gives a Keynote speech titled “<a href="http://programm.froscon.de/2015/events/1640.html" target="_blank">Beginning of the End or End of the Beginning?</a>”</p>
<p><span id="more-19422"></span>There are tons of development workshops at this event, so if you have never been to <a href="http://www.froscon.de/en/home/" target="_blank">FrOSCon</a>, we highly recommend you come or plan to attend one in the future.</p>
<h4>Landing Page</h4>
<p>The<a href="http://cyntss.github.io/opensuse-landing-page/" target="_blank"> landing page</a> is momentarily delayed and should be finished soon. There are still a few more things that need to be changed and feedback from the community has been helpful. The graphics increase the temperature of computers and use more than normal levels of RAM, so some slight adjustments need to be made before the new page is published.</p>
<h4>Leap</h4>
<p>On the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/" target="_blank">Factory Mailing List</a>, a discussion about new default fonts for Leap began and is moving along constructively.</p>
<p>One of the bigger discussions taking place about Leap is reviewing packages. Anyone who is able to review packages and wants to help can get involved with the <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:OpenSUSE_review_team" target="_blank">review team</a>. An option may be built into the<a href="https://en.opensuse.org/Portal:Build_Service" target="_blank"> Open Build Service</a> to help streamline the process of the <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:OpenSUSE_review_team" target="_blank">review team</a>, which will send packages for review to a reviewers who specialize in a certain area. The details aren’t clear just yet, but expect to hear more about this in the future.</p>
<h4>Asia Summit</h4>
<p>Two days ago we found out that the second <a href="https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/20/the-second-opensuse-asia-summit-is-arriving/" target="_blank">openSUSE Asia Summit</a> will take place in at the National Taipei University of Education in Taiwan from Dec. 5 to 6. With <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taipei_101" target="_blank">Taipei 101</a> in the background of this summit, it is certain to be stellar. If you’re in Asia or the Pacific, come to the summit and see how you can contribute to the openSUSE project!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/22/the-weekly-review-tumbleweed-gets-4-1-5-tw-shirt-at-froscon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The second openSUSE.Asia Summit is arriving!!!</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/20/the-second-opensuse-asia-summit-is-arriving/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/20/the-second-opensuse-asia-summit-is-arriving/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 21:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Manu Gupta]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Announcements]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Summit]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[summit]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19416</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[We are happy to announce the second openSUSE.Asia Summit following a glorious successful first edition. The conference will take place in Taiwan at National Taipei University of Education, Taiwan on December 5th and 6th, 2015. The summit is a great way for both openSUSE contributors, and, users to meet each other and have fun. The openSUSE community will get together, share [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>We are happy to announce the second openSUSE.Asia Summit following a glorious successful first edition. The conference will take place in Taiwan at National Taipei University of Education, Taiwan on December 5th and 6th, 2015.</p>
<p>The summit is a great way for both openSUSE contributors, and, users to meet each other and have fun. The openSUSE community will get together, share their experiences, and, learn free and open source technologies.<br />
<img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-19419" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/geeko_tail-300x225.jpg" alt="geeko_tail" width="300" height="225" /><br />
The goals of the Summit are</p>
<p>1. To promote openSUSE, its tools, and, other free open source software in Asia.<br />
2. To introduce people to the openSUSE Project, through a series of talks, discussions and workshops.<br />
3. To show prospective contributors, different various ways of contributing to the openSUSE Project and provide a platform for them to engage with contributors and find different avenues in the project that match their interests.</p>
<p>Normally, the openSUSE contributors and users communicated with each other online, thus it is a great opportunity to meet and talk face to face.  In addition, we have chance to learn free and open technologies, to share experiences with each other, and most of all, have fun at the Summit, and, in Taipei city.</p>
<p>Stay tuned!!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/20/the-second-opensuse-asia-summit-is-arriving/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>The weekly review: LibreOffice 5 in Tumbleweed, Leap trends, landing page almost ready</title>
		<link>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/13/the-weekly-review-libreoffice-5-in-tumbleweed-leap-trends-landing-page-almost-ready/</link>
		<comments>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/13/the-weekly-review-libreoffice-5-in-tumbleweed-leap-trends-landing-page-almost-ready/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 11:27:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Douglas DeMaio]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://news.opensuse.org/?p=19398</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Tumbleweed had four snapshots since our last weekly review, upgraded to a newer Kernel and has the latest LibreOffice 5, while Leap’s roadmap was published and version 42 is a trending topic on the Factory mailing list. Tumbleweed &#8211; TW Tumbleweed 20150807 snapshot last Friday gave many users an update they had been anticipating for [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/IMG_0321.png"><img class="alignright wp-image-19401 size-medium" style="margin: 10px;" src="https://news.opensuse.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/IMG_0321-169x300.png" alt="IMG_0321" width="169" height="300" /></a>Tumbleweed had four snapshots since our last weekly review, upgraded to a newer Kernel and has the latest <a href="https://blog.documentfoundation.org/2015/08/05/libreoffice-5-0-stands-out-from-the-office-suite-crowd/" target="_blank">LibreOffice 5</a>, while Leap’s roadmap was published and version 42 is a trending topic on the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/" target="_blank">Factory mailing list</a>.</span></p>
<h3><strong>Tumbleweed &#8211; TW</strong></h3>
<p>Tumbleweed <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00277.html" target="_blank">20150807 snapshot</a> last Friday gave many users an update they had been anticipating for a while; <a href="https://blog.documentfoundation.org/2015/08/05/libreoffice-5-0-stands-out-from-the-office-suite-crowd/" target="_blank">LibreOffice 5</a>!</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The updated version gives users improved user interface and design. LibreOffice 5 has a new AutoCorrect extension to simplify Emoji and other Unicode character input using </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">de facto</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;"> standard Emoji shortcodes, and other keywords surrounded by colons. It is now possible to crop an image with the mouse. Crop image, Format ▸ Image ▸ Crop menu entry and Graphic toolbar.</span></p>
<p><a href="http://lensfun.sourceforge.net/changelog/2015/05/10/Release-0.3.1-Changelog/" target="_blank">LensFun updated to 0.3.1</a> and improved performance when used with 32-bit float image buffers and introduced automated testing. It has new interchangeable lenses for Canon Fujifilm, Nikon, Olympus Panasonic, Samsung and Sony models.</p>
<p>In the <a href="http://lists.opensuse.org/opensuse-factory/2015-08/msg00284.html" target="_blank">20150810 snapshot</a>, the Linux Kernel was updated to 4.1.4, which is trailing the newest 4.1.5 stable kernel, but expect the newest stable kernel soon.</p>
<h4>Leap</h4>
<p><span id="more-19398"></span>Since the announcement of the Leap roadmap, it’s had several email topics circulating on the Factory mailing lists. Some people are wondering what packages have been accepted into Leap. The <a href="https://build.opensuse.org/project/show/openSUSE:42." target="_blank">list of packages</a> is more than 6,000 and more are expected.</p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://forum.suse.org.cn/leap.html" target="_blank">A list that updates every six hours</a> shows packages in Factory, which are not yet in Leap.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> Package maintainers need to make a conscious effort to submit items in Factory to Leap if they want them in 42.1.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Maintainers and developers submitting their packages to Leap </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">are asked to add the information to the <a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Major_features42.1" target="_blank">Leap Features </a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="https://en.opensuse.org/openSUSE:Major_features42.1" target="_blank">template</a> on the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">wiki. This will</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"> highlight new features and versions in Leap and, if you email </span><a href="mailto:ddemaio@suse.de"><span style="font-weight: 400;">ddemaio@suse.de</span></a><span style="font-weight: 400;">, I can highlight some of these new items in <a href="//news.opensuse.org/" target="_blank">news.opensuse.org</a></span>.</p>
<p>Leap 42.1 aligns with SUSE Linux Enterprise 12 Service Pack 1, which recently released a Beta. The source code from SP1 will be included in the second Milestone, which is expected to be released on Sept. 4. Leap and SLE share a common core, which aids in getting your contributions in future releases of SLE.</p>
<h4>Landing Page</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The <a href="http://cyntss.github.io/opensuse-landing-page/#" target="_blank">new landing page</a> for openSUSE is nearly finished. There are 17 languages for the new landing page and the page will help people unfamiliar with openSUSE a better understand the differences between Leap and Tumbleweed. The page will develop more as time goes on and contributors are more than welcome to refine it. Getting better information out to the public about the project is a step in the right direction.</span></p>
<h4>FrOSCon</h4>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Next weekend we will be at the <a href="https://www.froscon.de/en/home/" target="_blank">Free and Open Source Software Conferenc</a>e at the </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">University of Applied Sciences Bonn-Rhein-Sieg</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. The conference takes place August 22 – 23 at</span> <span style="font-weight: 400;"><a href="http://www.openstreetmap.org/?minlon=7.18247890472412&amp;minlat=50.7794532775879&amp;maxlon=7.18388938903809&amp;maxlat=50.7800941467285#map=19/50.77977/7.18318" target="_blank">Hochschule Bonn-Rhein-Sieg, Grantham-Allee 20, 53757 Sankt Augustin</a></span><span style="font-weight: 400;">. Come see us at our booth and watch the excellent presentations that will be at this FOSS event.</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>https://news.opensuse.org/2015/08/13/the-weekly-review-libreoffice-5-in-tumbleweed-leap-trends-landing-page-almost-ready/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
